I think one of my students has just
stumbled across gold,
and I've just told him to
turn it into a YouTube video.
And any business watching,
if you have a reel that
performs pretty well,
you should do exactly this.
So this is the Discord
that I help people on a daily basis.
I have no life.
So Matt here said,
"Had this pop on TikTok to like 60K.
The discourse is wild." So what he's doing
is he's getting a signal from the
internet that he's stumbled across gold.
Now, I'll show you here.
Matt's content is really good,
and he's one of those kind of annoying
creators where he's making amazing
content, and the main thing I can
actually just say to him
is keep doing what you're doing,
because there's no
way that he will continue to make content
like this and it won't pop off.
I'll show you a couple of his intros.
If you are chronically sleep deprived,
you should actually start taking creatine.
This guy is a liar.
Imagine a world where you could eat more
carbs with- What
should you do if you go over your calories
at night?
I like the scene changes, the cadence,
the editing.
So let's have a look at this video here
because I thought this
was some of his best
work, and if it's popping on TikTok,
it's a signal we should take seriously.
This red meat is killing you slowly.
Eating 100 grams of red meat can increase
your chance of cancer by 20%.
Even just using that Post-it Note,
we've got the meat,
we've got something to look
at, the text hidden behind. Now,
for most newbies and amateurs,
I would actually
say don't put this much effort into making
content because volume is your best
friend,
and if this slows down your edits being
like 10 hours an edit, it's just
not worth it. But Matt
is the exception here.
That Post-it Note took him maybe seven
seconds more of prep time, and just from a
visual, it looks great.
So even though everyone says it's high in
protein and that you should eat it, you
probably shouldn't. Right? Well,
except the people they tested it-
Great scene change
... they controlled nothing.
They didn't control their diet
or exercise.
And you notice that
when he's talking about diet
and exercise and doing this as
B-roll,
he's actually giving us something to look
at.
So even my eyes are like, "Oh, broccoli.
Oh, dumbbell." Actually, one thing here,
Matt, really like the well-developed
VMOs. Your vastus medialis oblique here
is giving you
credit where it's due.
Which are both massive factors-
Because he is baby-faced,
he's a young-looking dude, and
that can go against him in
this industry. But
when he starts picking up more momentum,
he will get the
gravitas and the status that goes with it,
and it will just snowball from there.
But anyway.
Long you live for. So the people-
Live long time. Love that.
Probably a nod to his Asian descent
...
studies on may have been smoking like a
chimney, arse on couch.
But let's look past
that because red meat can still increase
your chance of cancer
by 20%, which is a big number.
Now, what I can tell from here already
is he's done the research for this video,
and the only thing
that I could say that's bad about this
video is probably there's
too much information.
It would be quite easy to get overwhelmed.
It isn't. This 20%
is what we would call relative risk.
But there's another kind called absolute
risk.
So where we're now delving into the
research quite to some degree,
I'm thinking we're probably going to push
this into the two-minute mark, and that's
a signal to me that we should probably
consider making this a YouTube video.
Now, before you do anything with YouTube,
we need a title and thumbnail.
So when I was watching this and I
was thinking about a thumbnail that
we could use,
I actually thought about a cooking chef
that I randomly went for a dinner with in
Austin, and he's actually a fucking
really nice guy. So this
is just one of the ways
that I get to meet famous people,
being friends with Chris Williamson.
And again,
I've not been on his page in a long time,
but I just
know that I've seen some thumbnails
and my YouTube brain's gone, "Huh,
where are
they?" Because I've seen them recently.
Now,
these look quite different to the ones I'm
looking for, so maybe it was on
another one of his channels. Again,
10 million subscribers.
I am pretty livid at my friend Lucy Lord,
who cooks,
and she doesn't use YouTube,
which annoys me very much.
Okay, so these are the images.
So I must have been seeing it from over
here.
Oh, just 700K on his other one. Okay,
cool. You see these thumbnails now.
What I like about them
is he's using his likeness in the
thumbnail, but the
hero is very much the item in question.
So for instance, this baguette here,
the baguette is the hero, but if it
was just
the baguette on its own,
we would probably think, "Okay,
is this video about a
baguette?" But having him in the
background or even the fact it's on a
chopping
board, and again, human beings
are incredibly intuitive.
When we see something,
we straight away are going to try
and imagine what it's
about.
We're going to probably spend 75% of our
computing power on the
thumbnail,
and then we'll look at the title
afterwards.
So already for Matt,
I'm starting to think I want something
similar to this,
although his face isn't going to get us
that much likeness
because he isn't that big on YouTube.
So to give you another idea of why I'm
saying this, because I can just sound like
somebody who's mental, and again,
I appreciate this is pretty much what I do
on my
one-to-one calls.
I know you can't book them because I did
so many last year.
It's just too much.
I give too much energy. Okay, cool.
So here, the hero is the Prime bottle,
my likeness in the background.
The hero is the creatine gummies,
The hero is the AG1,
my likeness in the background.
You'll also notice for this AG1 video,
how is the packet unopened?
Yeah, I've got the green slush on my lips.
Well,
they're all different photos because you
can't have two things in focus at
the same time. Again,
I could say the creatine here is the hero,
but you
get the drift. Here you go.
The pen of Manjaroo is the hero.
That's my likeness. The Coke Zero
is the hero.
That's my likeness. The gummy is the hero.
Yeah, you're starting to get it now.
Again, it's quite a common theme
that I have the thing
that I'm talking about, and
then behind. Yeah, cool. All right,
so I'm going to give this to Matt as
his kind of concept to talk about.
So we have,
let's say, an image.
So first things first, let me see if I can
find a picture of him. And again, this
is only going to
be, oh, Jesus,
not a lot to pick from here. Fine.
Okay, let me see if there
are any grid posts. Oh, God.
I just lost so much time.
You're one of them. You're one of them.
And again, Matt, what I like about it
is he just, what the fuck is that?
No, I'm joking. He just gets on with it.
He's not there like, "Oh,
feel sorry for me.
I'm doing so many good reels." Met him at
one of Chris's shows actually as well.
Nice guy. Oh, he's done,
and he's remade this video before.
Okay, let's just see if we can save this.
And again, this probably won't look
that good. Just let me cook. All right.
Steak. Let's go raw steak on plate.
Or actually,
there might be something here already.
Red meat, good.
No, that got worse, didn't it?
That got worse. Okay.
I kind of like the angle
that Weissman goes with.
Probably like a little 45-degree angle.
These are all top-down, which
is really annoying, isn't it?
And by the way, this
is what you do before you have any video.
You want to make sure,
let's have a look on table Okay,
this could be it. Oh, Shutterstock.
Is that copyrighted, is it? Oh, no.
That would be terrible, wouldn't it?
But I do wonder if it's just going to let
me download from here, because I like
this because I want to put him in the
background just as an example. Right.
Photoshop. Duran Kartsal,
if you're watching this,
just start using Photoshop,
mate. Right. HDTV, this
is going to give us our thumbnail
dimensions.
Take these off and see if that works.
And it might seem like I'm just a fucking
whiz on this, which
granted, I probably am. Oh, no,
the copyright bit has
fallen off the bottom. Oh, no. Okay,
now this is just a crude one.
I would say to Matt,
go buy a fucking stake, you cunt, and
do this properly. Okay,
what I'm doing here
is I'm just going to use generative
fill, which is an AI.
I don't really want to stretch the image
that much more
because I quite like the dimensions
which it's in. Ooh,
a Nootonic focus pouch.
I actually think these
are probably going to be bigger than our
cans in the future.
They're minty. It's like a little teabag.
Chuck it in the cheek. They're sold out.
They'll be back in a couple of weeks.
And you get 20 servings per pack,
five packs for £25.
So, it's like 100 servings for £30.
It's good.
Right now,
I've got 50 milligrams of caffeine.
Just done it on the other side as well.
I've got 50 milligrams of caffeine
and 125 milligrams of cognizin going into
my
veins, getting the creative juices going.
Oh, sorry.
I already know what I want next.
Nice little arrow.
This one actually looks quite good. So,
I'm just going to download that one.
Again,
this is highly illegal what I'm doing.
But guys, I'm just working.
I'm just cooking something, all right?
Then we could say something like,
"Cancer." You see how this font
is just a bit
shit?
I should have some pretty good ones here.
Boom, boom, boom.
Let's go... Come on.
It's a bit of a rough deal trying to
make cancer look nice, isn't it?
Of course.
Let's just go with this one for a second.
We're going to- Oh, actually,
I've just thought,
can I use a question mark on this
font? Yes. And basically,
what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to put a little
drop shadow on it just to make it look a
bit nicer.
I know this can seem like I'm an absolute
wizard.
You're like, "Fuck, how
is this guy so handsome, six foot,
and good at
Photoshop?" But practice. Okay,
you see how it's disappearing there?
That's just a layers problem.
I've just got to push
that to the top layer.
And again,
I remember the first time I watched people
do this, I was
like, "Mate, slow the fuck down."
And then let's just bring this in.
Okay,
so we're going to make this a bit bigger,
spin that bad boy around, remove
background. And again,
I think I'm using a slightly older version
of Photoshop, but
maybe something like this.
It sounds crazy.
I'm going to give
that a drop shadow as well. And this
is just one of my concepts.
Probably would like Matt in the
background. Okay, cool.
So, I'm going to export that,
and I'll just call it Chewy, like Sui.
Cool.
Boom. Now what I need... I wonder
if anyone's still watching.
They're probably like,
"James just lost his fucking mind.
Just sat in his fucking office in the
middle of fucking nowhere, just being a
fucking mad cunt." So,
what I'm doing here on Thumbs Up TV
is I want to see how it
looks.
And I'm going to use dark mode because
most people use dark mode.
Let's test some titles. Here's one.
Does red meat really give you cancer?
The truth about red meat and cancer.
Here's another good one.
The dark truth behind red meat.
Whenever you say the dark, it
just does well. Now,
the reason we have to do this first
is that in your
introduction,
you have to pay off what the video
is about.
What I mean by that is
if he films the video first,
then makes the title, and then
goes with that and then never mentions the
dark truth, people are just going to
leave. They're just going to get into
that video and go, "This is shit." So,
what
he needs to do is, if you
were on the internet,
you would have thought there's a
dark truth about meat,
that it gives you cancer,
that it's 20% more likely to upset
your prostate,
and I'm here to tell you it's not true,
or is it?
And then he gets into the setup,
then he does the video or whatever it is.
So now I'm going to go back to Matt,
and I'm going to say to him, "Hey, mate.
Decided to do some of your packaging for
you.
How great am I?" See all these threads
I've got to get through.
That's why I'm ill.
I just devote my life,
I just devote my life.
Probably thinking, "Wow,
does this guy really go to
that much effort for his
people?" Yeah, he does. Now,
whilst we're here,
I know it's been quite a bit
already. Alex, right,
I'm not going to lie to you.
He put in a pretty dead video the other
day.
Look, I know you can't probably read this,
but I said, "Look, no offense, but that
was shit." I said, "What does
that mean?" Okay,
so he reckons he's done a better
reel today. I know this
is a bit of a tangent, but bear with.
You're doing cardio every day,
but your body's still... Okay,
let's listen to him.
It could be all right.
You're doing cardio four
or five times a week,
and you're getting a good sweat on,
but your body still isn't changing,
and this-
It's better than the last one
...
it's one of the most common things you see
people do.
They spend so much time on the cardio
machine-
The thing is, mate, I'm getting bored now
... trying to burn away all the fat
and then get fr-
Hook, good. Setup, bit boring
... when nothing changes.
Unless you're tracking your food,
it doesn't matter how
much cardio you do and how much you sweat.
If you're still eating too much, you will-
No. Dead. Not a fan. Look,
what this should have
been is working out how far you'd need
to run to lose weight.
You should have run a 3K, a
5K,
and a 10K on three days trying to find out
unless I control my calories.
There's no stakes, brother.
You're just on the balcony chatting.
Matt, deadass,
just going to copy your creative one with
the other plates centered,
me in the background, just like showing.
This guy knows. He knows.
Matt Chewy is on the sui. By the way,
I heinously
undercharged for this.
He's using an Android, this guy.
Let's see if there's that gif.
What's that, brother? Ooh, brother.
What's that, brother? Ooh. Okay.
So basically, what I want, we had the
signal from the matrix,
and the matrix said to us, "We like this
video. Time to double down,
make it a YouTube video." Most of my best
hitters, all
reels as well, that perform really well.
So, that is an insight behind the madness.
My silver play button,
which helps you do all of this on YouTube,
we haven't put
the price up for it yet.
There'll be a link in the description.
You should join it.
It's usually a $1,000 course.
I'm pretty sure it's like $199.
So, join that or don't. I'm not your dad.
Well, I hope not.
All right,
I've got to the point where I'm chewing
the zin now, so...
And if you don't want to buy my mentorship
or any of my stuff, just buy some
Nootonic, you fucking, you dogs.
Nootonic.com. Put it through the business.
Business expense. What?
You can get a coffee machine through the
office.
You should get Nootonic. Anyway,
if you did like that,
there's a video here.
All right. Bye.